All right, well, good morning, everyone.
Thanks, John, for sharing with us this morning,
and welcome, everyone here to HMCC.
If we haven't met yet, my name is Pete.
I'm one of the pastors here as well,
and it's my joy to be able to share
God's word with you this morning.
If you have a Bible with you and you'd like to open it,
you can open to Matthew 28.
We're gonna be looking at some verses there this morning,
and everything will be on the screen as well,
but we always like to have the word of God
open in front of us.
And as we gather here this morning,
this is the start of a new season,
and as John mentioned, or Pastor Josh mentioned earlier,
We're celebrating 30 years together here as a church, and I'm really excited to start
this season with a sense of purpose, with a sense of anticipation, with a sense of God
doing something great here within our church community.
And so this is a great time to visit us if you are visiting us for the first time today,
which we know many people are.
I want to especially welcome those of you who are here as college students or graduate
students, maybe new to the area, new to the U of M campus right now.
College is a really exciting time to build community, to explore different interests,
to ask big questions, to prepare for the future, all of that.
And we're really excited that you're here within our church community to do that as well.
I think being part of a church is a really important thing to growing in your faith
or even discovering who Jesus is.
And so we're so glad that you're visiting us here this morning,
and hopefully God will work in your life during your college years.
Some of you may be new today and you're not a college student too,
and you're like, man, there's a lot of college students around here.
Well, yeah, the biggest chunk of people within our church is our college ministry.
We're so thankful for that.
But I'm also really glad if you're here in our church, you'll see lots of working people,
lots of families, kids running around, teenagers, babies galore, which is all really great.
And, you know, we love being part of a church where we can have kind of multiple generations
here within the same spiritual family.
And, you know, one thing I've found is that people who are not students who are part of
our church are usually people who really have a heart for ministry to the next generation,
whether that's babies or kids or youth or college students.
So I'm really thankful for the community God has given us here.
And I hope for all of us, you know, whether you are new to our church
or whether you're continuing with our church,
hopefully this will be a great morning to help us really focus in
on who we're called to be as a church family.
I know some of you here, you're trying to decide on a church to call home.
And as Pastor Josh mentioned, there are lots of great churches and ministries
around this campus and this city.
so we hope you'll check out some different groups and find a place to belong.
You know, our church isn't for everyone, but we would love it if you find your spiritual home here.
And just so you know, over the next couple of weeks as well,
today we're actually going to be focusing on our church's mission.
Next Sunday we're going to talk about the vision we believe God has given our church,
and then after that we're going to be sharing our theme for the year,
which we like to have an annual theme to kind of bring focus to things for the year.
So we'll be doing that over the next couple of Sundays.
But this morning is an opportunity to think about why we exist here as a church,
and even what kind of church we would want to be part of.
And so even to think about that this morning,
I'd like to start with kind of a brief illustration of,
some of you may have heard of this thing called the Svalbard Global Seed Vault.
Is anyone familiar with this or heard about this before?
Yeah, a bunch of you have. That's cool.
And it looks sort of like an evil genius's lair, which I think is really cool.
But this, I think it's in Norway, and this exists as like a doomsday vault.
And so this is built like deep into a mountainside, and the purpose of it existing is actually to store seed samples from around the world.
And so it actually, it's only about a third full right now.
It's only at a third capacity, but at a third capacity it has like 1.2 million different seed samples.
And they store these there in like deep freeze.
I think it maintains a constant temperature of like negative 18 degrees Celsius, and they're stored deep underground.
And all these workers are there, and their job is to actually maintain all these different aisles and stacks of seeds that are there and maintain all of it, manage all of it, with the idea that someday there might be a global catastrophe or even a regional climate breakdown or something like that, where just the ecosystem will melt down and where the world actually needs to be restored agriculturally from scratch.
And so the idea is, if something horrible like that happens, that these seeds will be broken
out of the seed vault and taken and restore the agriculture.
And really the idea is, keep the world from starving to death.
That's actually the big idea.
It's like, man, these seeds, if we keep them safe, if we preserve them, if we steward them
well, then they're going to actually keep the world alive.
They're going to keep the world from starving.
And I find this fascinating by itself.
I think it's a very cool thing to exist.
and I would love to visit it someday, although I don't know if they take visitors. But I think this
is a really fitting analogy for us to think about as we start today's message and think about as
Christians, you know, how do we live? Why do we live? Why do we do the things that we do? And I think
for all of us here, maybe you are somebody who is a Christian and you've been a follower of Jesus
for a long time. Maybe you are exploring the Christian faith and wondering what it is about.
But one thing that as Christians we believe is that we have these seeds of eternal life
Jesus told regularly talked about the kingdom of god as something that is like a seed
A seed that when it's planted it grows into a great tree
It bears a lot of fruit and that fruit is not just nice fruit to enjoy that is the fruit of salvation
That's the fruit of life of eternal life
It's something that the whole world actually needs
And for us this morning we get to think about you know
what do we do with those seeds that we ourselves possess and carry? And will we just kind of keep
them here in our own concrete bunker of a building that God has provided for us? Or will we actually
take them out into the world? And so each of us has to answer these kinds of questions. What am I
living for? And even us together as a church, what are we living for? What are we doing here together
as a spiritual family? And so today, as I mentioned, we're going to be focusing on our
church's mission and looking at a specific passage to do that. And our church's mission is transforming
lost people into Christ's disciples who will then transform the world. And if you've been with our
church for a while, you're probably very familiar with this. If you're new, maybe you're hearing this
for the first time. But I know for myself, I mean, John shared his story earlier. I came as a freshman
to the University of Michigan in 1999, and then I joined our church here in January of 2000 when I
first placed my faith in Jesus. This is the only church I've ever been a part of now for the past
26 years. And what has kept me here, what has kept me grounded, what keeps me going week to week
is knowing that this is the mission that I'm committed to and that our church family is
committed to together. As you look at this mission statement, you'll probably recognize that this
is simply a restatement of what we see Jesus telling his disciples in Matthew 28. And so we're
going to look at Matthew 28 verse 16 to 20 together today, and I'll go ahead and read these verses for
us. It says this, now the eleven disciples went to Galilee, to the mountain to which Jesus had
directed them. And when they saw him, they worshipped him, but some doubted. And Jesus came
and said to them, all authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Go therefore and make
disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy
Spirit, teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always to
the end of the age. Amen. We'll pause there. Let me just pray for us one more time as we've read
God's word. God, thank you for your holy word. Thank you that through these written pages that
we get to hear you speak to us and know that you have a message for us. You have a purpose for our
lives. You have something greater that you're calling us to be part of and something that you
want us to live out together as the family of the church. Please bless us, Lord, in this time that
we will share together, looking into your word. Speak to each one of us personally. Speak to us
together as a church family. And help us, Lord, to receive your word and to respond with faith, God,
because we trust you. We want to know you more. We want to live for your purpose in our lives. So
thank you, God. Bless our time together. It's in Jesus' name that we pray. Amen. Amen. So as we
look into this passage together, many of you may be familiar with this because this is a passage,
especially verses 18 to 20, that is commonly called the Great Commission. And it's really
important because these are some of Jesus' last words that he spoke to his followers before he
actually ascended back to the Father, to God's heavenly kingdom, from where he will come again.
And this tells us what Jesus wanted his followers to do after he left them, the mission that he wanted
them to continue. And so we're stepping into this story as Jesus' disciples went to meet him on a
mountaintop in Galilee. And when they saw him, it's really interesting to note how they responded
to him. And we see in the story, when they saw Jesus, they responded to him with worship and
doubt. Those are two kind of funny things to see side by side, aren't they? But what do we see when
we unpack this a little bit? First thing we notice is it says they saw him. And that by itself is
actually really significant. This tells us that they weren't, that Jesus was truly resurrected
from the grave. He truly rose from the dead. And he is not some hallucination. He is not some
apparition. In fact, this isn't the only place in the Bible where we see Jesus risen from the dead
throughout the Gospels. Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John. We see Jesus meeting his disciples in
private locked rooms where he suddenly appeared to them. We see him sitting down and eating with
them. We see his disciples touching his wounds in his hands and his feet and his side. We see
hundreds of disciples meeting Jesus and seeing him at the same time on mountaintops, like over and
over again, over a period of weeks, we see Jesus' disciples meeting him and seeing he truly was
risen from the grave. And that's a really, really powerful thing. So here we're seeing one of those
moments when Jesus truly rose from the grave, that he's really standing in front of them, and
then it kind of makes sense then that they worshiped him. And again, this is a very profound
statement. It's an important statement. Because what we believe as Christians, as people of the
Bible, is that worship is only properly given to God. God is the only one who should be worshipped.
Worship of anything else is what the Bible calls idolatry. It's taking something that should be
given to God and giving it to another person. And if we just pay attention to the world around us,
We'll notice that this causes all kinds of problems when people turn their worship in
the wrong direction.
And when people start to worship another person, that leads to massive problems.
When people start to worship their career or worship their studies or their GPA or worship
their reputation or worship another person's approval of them, this just leads to all kinds
of breakdowns as we get things out of order in our lives.
So here when we see the disciples worshiping Jesus, the fact that they are worshiping him means they recognize that he is truly God.
That he's not just a special human being.
He's not just a prophet or a wise teacher or a miracle worker.
He's not merely any of these things.
They recognize Jesus as God because of everything that they have seen in his life.
And they've been following him for a while now.
They witnessed his teaching. They witnessed his humility. They witnessed miracles. They witnessed
servanthood. They witnessed him driving out evil spirits. They witnessed him doing all of these
things miraculously, even calling somebody else out of the grave back to life. They witnessed him
doing all of these things, and then they saw him crucified, being killed and executed on a cross,
buried in the grave and rising again, just as he had predicted beforehand what happened.
And from all of this put together and all the older prophecies of the Bible that pointed ahead
to him, they're now able to recognize this must actually be God. And that's important because here
we not only see the disciples worshiping Jesus, but Jesus actually accepts their worship. He
doesn't tell them, hey, stop that. I'm not God. He accepts it. And here's the thing. Like, if Jesus
was not actually God, and he accepted them worshiping him, that actually makes him a monster.
Actually means something really bad about him. If he's willing to be worshiped by these people,
if he were not really God. But he receives that worship, because it's the right thing to do. It's
the right response. And for us this morning, as we look into this story, we should ask ourselves the
question, do we recognize Jesus for who he really is? Do we recognize him as God in human flesh,
as the savior of the world who died and rose again, not just as a random historical event,
but because that actually restores our relationship with God. That when we trust in him, that he died
for us, paid the penalty for us, that because of that now our rebellion against God is forgiven
and cleansed and washed away, and we can be restored to relationship with God. If we recognize
that, that a life of worship is the proper response, and this is actually what every single person
needs to hear and needs to respond to and live out. So they worshiped him. But then, I love this,
it says, but some doubted. I love that this is here. And for a few reasons, I love this because
I think when you read the Bible, you realize the Bible is really honest about our human condition.
It never sugarcoats it or covers anything up.
It's really honest that we struggle to believe and to trust God.
And at least for me, I think that's encouraging.
I think it's encouraging that when you read the whole Bible, you see all over the place,
there are some really raw examples of things like doubt and fear and pain and anxiety and foolish decisions and depression
and just a whole mess of things that are normal to human life.
And because of that, I think when we see, okay, they worshiped him, but some doubted,
I think this has like the ring of truth to it.
This is not a myth or a fable or a work of fiction.
If it was, maybe Matthew would have written something like,
we all believed wholeheartedly and never doubted for a moment.
And we would all read it and say, really?
Really? You don't have any doubt?
You don't have any questions?
You don't struggle for a moment? Really, Matthew?
But no, when it says some doubted, it's like, okay, that sounds real.
That sounds true.
That sounds genuine.
And I think a few other things we see from this doubt in this passage is, I mean, partly
it's clear that Jesus is not offended by our honest doubts and questions.
And I think for some of us here, maybe you've got those.
Maybe you grew up in church your whole life, and for the first time, you're asking questions.
Wait, is this real?
Can I really trust this?
For those of you who are freshmen,
maybe right now you're like, yeah, I'm fine.
I'm a strong Christian.
And then you're gonna go to your first philosophy class
and you're gonna be floored.
And don't worry, all the questions
that you will hear on campus,
all the objections, the criticisms of the Christian faith,
there are great answers to those questions.
There's no question or doubt that's too big for God.
But for some of us,
we might have never encountered that before.
We might deeply struggle with it.
It's okay to come to God with those doubts and struggles.
Jesus is not offended by your questions
or even the fact that you struggle with your faith.
And so Jesus isn't offended by that.
Another thing I think is clear here
is Jesus doesn't wait for all of our doubts
to be resolved before he gives us a calling.
Jesus doesn't wait for all of our doubts
That's really important to recognize and understand here.
His disciples, they're in front of him.
Some of them, they're doubting.
They're like, is this real?
Really, really, that's it, really?
And they're struggling, but Jesus is like,
I'm going to go ahead and give you this calling anyway.
We're going to unpack in just a minute.
And this means that following Jesus really requires faith.
A lot of us, we want to have certainty before we respond to God's calling.
What Jesus calls us to is a life of faith.
If I could put it this way, I think for many of us,
we would love it if following Jesus looked like following directions on Google Maps.
We would really like that, right?
Like maybe for some of you, you're here and you're like, okay, I want to know the route from the University of Michigan in Ann Arbor, Michigan to Silicon Valley where the career of my dreams is waiting for me.
That's what I want to know.
And so I put that into Google Maps and it shows me the whole route.
It shows me even two alternative routes.
I can pick and choose which one I'm going to go on.
And it shows me where the construction is along the way and where I'm going to have to take a detour around something.
And it's not just going to be straight through.
And I can pick that route, and up front, I know every turn I'm going to have to make.
I can even map out pit stops at gas stations, or Buc-ee's, or whatever else I want to stop
at, right?
I can map that out, and I can know exactly how long it's going to take me to get there.
My route is crystal clear.
For many of us, we want following Jesus to look like this.
We think, okay, Jesus, if you tell me, maybe even for my college years, maybe for my family
life, maybe for my career, maybe for what high school or middle school is going to look like.
If I have a map and I know what it's going to look like, okay, Jesus, then I will follow you.
I will say yes, because I know up front what I'm getting into. But the thing with Jesus is
following him does not look like following directions on Google Maps. It looks a little
bit more like Jesus just giving you a compass and saying, go that way. He doesn't tell us what
the whole route is going to be like beforehand. But he tells us the direction he wants us to go in.
And he wants us to trust him. Again, not waiting for every doubt to be cleared away, but to say,
Jesus, you've shown me the direction you want me to go. And I can hold that compass in my hand.
Maybe it looks a lot like a Bible or like your Bible app or something. Maybe it looks like
being part of God's mission. Maybe it looks like living out your faith in a community.
So I have my compass, and I have the leading of God's Holy Spirit, and I have people around me
to support me and encourage me on this journey, and I can start taking steps of faith in the
direction that compass tells me to go in. That's what a life of faith in following Jesus looks
like. And so as we see here, as we kind of follow through the rest of the story, there's something
specific that Jesus is calling us to, a direction he wants us to go in, and he's going to lead us
along that path. And what we start to see as we look through the rest of the passages is, first
off, that this is a global calling. It actually encompasses everything. And, like, I don't know
how much we think about this, like, to be part of something that actually encapsulates the whole
world, to be part of a greater purpose. I remember seeing an example of this that I thought was,
it really stuck with me. About 20 years ago, a little while back, I went on a missions trip
with our church to India, to northern India, up near the Himalayas. And I remember when we were
up there, I got to see something. Somebody told me a story, a pastor up there told me a story that I
thought really stuck out. And to understand the story real quick, first I have to just ask, how
many of you here are Coca-Cola fans? Not Pepsi, right? Coke? Like you have to ask at the restaurant,
Pepsi or Coke, right? Because you got to know. I'm a Diet Coke person, okay? So I got to know.
no diet Pepsi. That tastes weird. Leaves a bad taste in my mouth. Okay, so I'm a Coke person.
But I don't know if you know this, but Coca-Cola, their slogan or their motto, whatever, is actually
refresh the world. It's refresh the world. And so Coca-Cola's all over the world. And I remember
seeing an example of this when I was in northern India. This pastor told me a story that he was
actually going up into the Himalayas to like these really high villages to tell them about Jesus
Christ and what he'd done. And he was going up into these mountains and he had to like hike up
these steep paths and use like the mountain climbing equipment and stuff. And he was going
up to one of these villages and he's thinking, I'm going to this place. They've probably like never
seen anyone from the outside world before. And I'm going to tell them about Jesus. And as he's
walking up this mountain path, he sees a Sherpa coming down the other direction. And he realizes
the Sherpa is actually carrying on his back this contraption to carry Coca-Cola to that mountain
village so that they would be able to have a bottle of Coke way up in the remote Himalayas.
And I realized, like, I mean, partly he was kind of discouraged by that. He's like, oh man,
they got Coke before they got Jesus. But I was like, man, like, there's this organization that
wants to refresh the world. And what that comes down to is like one guy carrying a backpack with
that head strap deal and like carrying Coca-Cola up the mountain to reach this village. That's like,
Like, man, do we see ourselves as part of something like that?
Because what Jesus tells us here is, this is a global calling.
The first thing he says is, I have all authority.
I have all authority.
There's a bunch of references there if you want to look at that.
But throughout the four Gospels, you see Jesus having real authority over, like, everything.
Like, you see him.
He says there's authority in his teaching, authority to forgive sins, which belongs to God alone,
authority over sicknesses and diseases, authority over evil spirits, authority even over the weather,
the winds and the waves obey him. He has authority over everything. And now here when he says
all authority, he's trying to make clear, okay, it's not just these few things you've seen me do.
Now, no, it's over the whole universe, the whole cosmos. I'm the king over the whole cosmos and
everything at every level from planets and stars and galaxies to kings and nations and governors
to decisions you make, to relationships you're in, to education you're pursuing, to work you're doing,
to family you're raising, to all these things. All of it now comes under the authority of Jesus
Christ. And based on that authority, now he says, I want you to go to all nations. I want you to go
to every nation of the world. And for us, when we think of that word nation, we think of like
political nation states. Here that's not the exact meaning we're talking about. The word nation
actually just means like a people group, a tribe, a people group that might be defined by things like
language or culture or some aspects of geography, a people group that needs to hear. You see, I want
you to go to every nation. Why? Because the whole world is far from God. The whole world needs to hear
the gospel of Jesus Christ and what he has done for us. And today there are actually two to three
billion people, more than one in four people on earth, that have never heard the gospel of Jesus
Christ that many of us here consider very familiar. And that's why for us as a church, a couple
things are really important to us. One of those is just being involved in the mission of God. And
there's so many ways to do that that I'll mention a little bit later as well. But we also really
have a value and vision of transculturalism, and that's something we'll talk more about next week
as well, but we believe the church should actually be a family of God that actually can embrace and
welcome and be formed around just different cultures, people from different backgrounds,
not just having one type of people group in the church, but being able to cross cultural
boundaries for the sake of the gospel and living out our faith together. That's really important
to us? If we're going to reach all nations, how about we start with the nations that are in the
church together? And this is a mission that Jesus called his followers to based on his authority,
and he told them what to do and how to do it. And that's kind of the biggest chunk we're going to
focus on here today is actually the calling to make disciples. This is what Jesus calls us to do.
And here I just want to notice that. Jesus does his primary calling. He didn't say go build a
church building every nation of the world, although church buildings are great. He didn't say go and
just have meetings every nation of the world. He said specifically make disciples. And what does
that mean? The word disciple in Greek is mathetes, and that means a learner or a student or an
apprentice. And so for us, when we think student, we probably think more like a classroom environment,
like your classroom in high school. Or maybe some of you, you're in undergrad or grad school,
and you're thinking about your organic chemistry lecture
where it's going to be like 500 people
listening to a professor talk
or your EECS 183 class.
You're going to go in,
it's going to be 200 people
all listening to some guy talk about coding, right?
And you think like that environment,
that's not what we're talking about here.
In the Near Eastern world,
the rabbinic traditions were that
if somebody was a student,
an apprentice of a rabbi like Jesus,
that meant like a rigorous, immersive lifestyle.
It meant copying every aspect of their lives, not just learning knowledge.
And so imagine for a second you're in organic chemistry, maybe honors or honors, honors, orgo.
You're there in your lecture, and you go up to the professor after class.
You say, professor, I want to learn everything you know.
I want to become just like you.
And the professor's like, well, you can come to office hours.
I'll answer your questions.
I'll help you with, you know.
and then you're like, no, actually what I had in mind
is I would love to sleep on your couch
and I want to take care of your pets
and I want to see how you make breakfast
and how you raise your kids.
How about that?
Professor's like, what?
That's what we're talking about.
That's what following Jesus
or following one of these ancient rabbis
would actually look like.
And so here, like one of the phrases
that was a common phrase back then
for a student, for a disciple of a rabbi
was cover yourself in the dust of his feet.
Cover yourself in the dust of his feet.
Turn to someone next to you and say,
cover yourself in the dust of Jesus' feet.
So this is not a casual kind of one day a week
sort of faith on a Sunday morning.
This encompasses all of life.
And specifically, Jesus tells them a couple things
that I think are really significant.
He tells them, make disciples by baptizing disciples.
Baptizing disciples.
And just so you know, some of you,
maybe you're coming from different backgrounds.
Again, I did not grow up in the Christian faith.
I remember as a kid, I had no real understanding of what baptism was or why you did it.
So some of you may have different understandings of this.
But what baptism is about is the practice of dunking somebody underwater and then coming back up out of the water again.
You don't leave them down there.
Okay, they come back up.
So you dunk somebody underwater, and what that symbolizes, what that symbolizes is actually forgiveness and identity.
So when somebody is dunked underwater in baptism,
that visualizes being washed clean and forgiven
of our rebellion against God,
what the Bible calls sin.
And then it also visualizes identifying with Jesus
that you died with him,
and then you come back to life with him.
This is what's described in Romans chapter six,
three and five.
It says, do you not know that all of us
who have been baptized into Christ Jesus
were baptized into his death?
For if we have been united with him
in a death like his, we shall certainly be united with him in a resurrection like his.
So what this is describing is not just kind of an empty religious ritual. This is actually
describing knowing that we're forgiven by placing our faith in Jesus, by his grace, and now we're
completely identifying with him. Jesus, I've died with you. I've risen with you. Now my life is about
you. Everything, that kind of discipleship where it's like, it's immersive. It's my whole life.
everything committed to you. And he says, make disciples not just by baptizing disciples, but also
by teaching disciples. Now, wait, I thought we weren't doing the classroom thing. So what's this
about? What kind of teaching is this? Well, this isn't teaching to win Bible quizzes or to accumulate
more Bible knowledge or get a degree or something, even though those are fine things. This is teaching,
Jesus says, teach them to observe. And that word observe actually means obey or keep. So it's
teaching them to obey all that I have commanded, he said. And from here, what we need to understand
is mature discipleship is not about only knowledge about the Bible or about Jesus. Mature discipleship
is about actually obeying Jesus' calling on our lives and all the things that he has taught us
about. That's what this is about. And so when Jesus says, make disciples, baptize them, teach them,
do these things, this is now what we're called to live in ourselves and what we're called to help
others do. And when we think about what does that look like in the life of our church today,
not just kind of a nice idea, but how we actually live it out, what we like to share with people
is that in our church, we want everyone to belong, believe, and become. Belong, believe,
and become. Turn to someone next to you and say, belong, believe, and become. Okay? And this in
specific ways. So when we think about this, I'll just unpack this briefly for us. Belonging, we're
not just talking about kind of general belonging, but belonging specifically in a biblical community
of grace and truth. You see beautiful pictures of this, like in Matthew chapter 9, where Jesus
goes to Matthew, the tax collector's house, and it says he's hanging out with tax collectors and
sinners and people that normally a religious person like Jesus, a rabbi like Jesus, normally
wouldn't associate with. And in fact, people start criticizing him. They start saying, Jesus,
why are you hanging out with those people, people like that? You shouldn't be hanging out with them.
But Jesus says, hey, it isn't the healthy that need a doctor. It's sick people who need a doctor.
I've come here not to call righteous people, but sinners. This is why I'm here, to build this kind
of community where people can experience grace and truth. And this is what life group in our
church is all about. If you haven't signed up for one already, you can go ahead and sign up for one
today. We would love for you to see it. What we want to do in these communities is be communities
built around Jesus, around the Bible, but communities of extraordinary grace and extraordinary truth.
That means we can be so gracious and merciful to each other. It makes us feel like we can be loved
and accepted, encouraged, and cared for. We can also be really honest. Just like the Bible is
honest about the human condition and everything we go through, in these communities we can be
really honest about our struggles, about our fight with temptation, about the things we're
going through in life, and know that we're going to be loved and cared for, and we're also going to
hear the truth of what the Bible says about the call to follow Christ and his purpose for our
lives. A biblical community of grace and truth, that's what that is about. And then from there,
we really pray that people will believe in the gospel and commit to the church. And you get a
beautiful picture of this as well in Acts 2, 41 to 47. You see that Peter preaches this big
sermon to the city of Jerusalem, 3,000 people believe in Jesus, and they're immediately baptized
like we just talked about. And then it says they devoted themselves to the apostles' teaching,
to the fellowship, to the breaking of bread, to prayer. They start living out their faith together.
And so this is just what we want to emulate within our church, that when people believe
that they're baptized into the Christian faith, that they're living out their faith in community,
and that aspect of commitment is important. I think for some people that word commitment
kind of sounds like a dirty word, like, oh, I don't want to commit to something. But if you think about
it, like, commitment is one of those things, you want everybody else to commit to you, but we don't
want to commit to anything. Like, that's just kind of how it works. But in the Bible, like, the
descriptions of the church we see, like, the most common descriptions of the church are a spiritual
family or a body with many parts. And if you think about that, like, a family, do you, is it like one
day you're part of a family and the next day you're not part of the family and the next day you're back
in again. No, it's like if you're part of a family, you're in the family. You're committed to those
relationships. How about with your body? Do you like take off your arm one day and like reattach
it the next? Like no, you're a part of the body. You have a meaningful role. You're important
as part of that body. And this is something we want to encourage. I mean, many of you here,
you're checking out different churches and ministries. That's great. What I would share
with you is you don't need to commit to this church. We would love it if you did. If you're
not going to commit to this church. Commit to another church, because that's going to help you
grow spiritually. That's going to be valuable for your growth, and that's going to build up others
around you as well. And so we want people to believe in the gospel and commit to the church, to be part
of this worshiping, growing, praying, serving community. And then as we do that, we also want
everyone to become a disciple who seeks Jesus, serves, and is sent to make disciples. And we'll
look at another picture of this next week in Acts chapter 13. But notice Jesus said, teach them to
observe all that I have commanded you? Well, it's hard to sum up everything Jesus commanded us to do.
That's a lot. But think about some basic things, like seeking Jesus, like having an abiding
relationship with Christ, like we see in John 15, that we abide in him and we bear much fruit. Or
like serving. Matthew writes in Matthew 23, Jesus said, the greatest among you will be your servant.
That's what Jesus modeled and demonstrated for us. He wants us to be those who serve. And then today
we're talking about being sent to make disciples, and that's in so many ways. We can make disciples
around our campus and city as we reach out to different people, or even through things like
short-term missions trips that we do as a church, or through one-year internships with AMI that
we're part of, or through intentionally discipling our children as they grow up within our
households, or maybe starting a Bible study at work, investing in the next generation, or leading
a life group or ministry team. There are all these different ways that we can actually live
out our faith in that being sent to make disciples. But imagine for a moment, these are kind of big
ideas, but just imagine what this could look like for you. I know for many of us, many people
share with me, starting a new season, there's a lot of anxiety that comes with that. Maybe some
of us here, we're actually feeling really anxious about starting college, starting grad school,
starting high school, starting, you know, whatever else it may be, starting a new job, new season of
family, new kids on the way, feel this anxiousness about this, what would it be like to bring that
anxiety to a community, a biblical community of grace and truth, to there be supported and
encouraged by the love of God, to be invited into the grace and mercy of Jesus, to be really lifted
up from that, and then like, wow, I can come on a Sunday, and even in the midst of my struggles
and my doubts, I can still be part of a worshiping community, or I fix my eyes on Jesus, I realize
he's bigger than those things that I feel so much anxiety about. And I hear God's word and I learn
to trust and believe and follow Jesus. And God is setting me free from that anxiety as I seek him
and worship him. And then while I go to class and I see somebody else struggling with anxiety, I go
to work, I see somebody else struggling, and man, now I have something to share with them. I can
invite them into the same grace and mercy that I have experienced and live that out together. This
what that can look like on a regular basis. And I think for us as a church, this is what we need to
kind of wrestle with, is what kind of church community will we be? Will we be a community of
faith that really lives this out together, or will we settle for something else? I realize that
churches around the world, around the country, see themselves in different ways. Some of you may have
grown up in lots of different kinds of churches, which is awesome. There are some churches that
see themselves as maybe maintaining a denominational or theological tradition. That's great. Maybe other
churches see themselves rooted as like a more of a cultural or ethnic church that is about that
tradition, that background. That's great. Maybe for others, it's different things. It's, you know,
like a club or a friend group to be part of, people to hang out with and have a good time with,
or maybe even as a spiritual business, delivering Christian goods and services, and you pay your
do somehow. It could be all kinds of stuff. I thank God that he works in all different kinds of
churches. I praise God for that. For us as a church, what are we going to be? I really pray that we
will see ourselves and understand ourselves as a church that's built on a mission, a mission that
we believe Jesus has called us to. And that, again, that mission is transforming lost people
into Christ's disciples who will then transform the world. And what we really believe, and the
reason our church is here on the U of M campus and in Ann Arbor, Michigan, is we really believe that
if lives are transformed here, that the world will literally be transformed around us. I love
it that the nations of the world gather here in Ann Arbor, over a hundred nations on the U of M
campus. I love it that the next generation comes here for training and to prepare for the rest of
their lives. Literally, if we live out our faith and if we live out this mission here, the people
that we reach, the people who grow as disciples in our church, the people we live out our faith
together with here will go around the country and to the ends of the earth and will literally
change the world because of what they've experienced here within our church community.
And so what could this look like as we live out our mission together this year? God's been really
faithful to our church over the last 30 years. And as we look ahead, I know for some of us, maybe
there's even a struggle or a doubt that comes with this. Maybe for some of us like, man, I want
to live for something bigger than myself. I want to be part of a global calling. I want to be part
of what God's doing in the world, but I doubt. I feel inadequate. I struggle. I'm not sure if I'm
good enough for this. I don't know what impact I could have on the lives of others. I'm not sure
how to just manage myself right now. But you know, here's where I love it, that whenever God gives us
a calling, he also gives us a promise.
And when Jesus gave this calling,
go and make disciples of all nations,
he also said,
I'm going to be with you.
I'm going to be with you. And this is the confidence
that we can have today as we look ahead
into this coming year. Jesus is going
to be with us in all the struggles
we face, in all the doubts that we need
to try to figure out, in all
the temptations that we need to say
no to, in all the opportunities
that we need to say yes to.
Jesus is going to be with us through all of that.
And so as we wrap up this time,
I just want to give you just three quick things
to think about reflecting and responding to this morning.
The first of those is I just want to encourage you
to hear Jesus' calling personally.
Hear Jesus' calling personally.
I believe that this calling, the Great Commission,
I believe it's given to the church
and it's given to every individual Christian.
Can you hear this as a calling
not just to this church, this organization today,
but as a calling that you yourself would hear
and be part of,
that Jesus is speaking to you today,
calling you by name,
saying, I want you to be part of this.
Can you hear that personally today?
I know this is a calling of Jesus on your life.
The second thing I would encourage you with
is to prayerfully consider your next steps in this.
What does that look like for you?
And for some of you,
maybe you're just here for the first time,
you're checking things out,
and maybe a great first step
would actually be to sign up for a life group
like we've been talking about.
For some of you,
maybe it's actually doing other things
like getting involved in serving in our church
because, wow, yeah, I want to be somebody who serves
like Jesus told me to.
I want to grow in that in some way this year.
Maybe it's growing your devotional life,
learning to seek Jesus day by day in his word and in prayer.
Maybe it's learning to mentor somebody.
I had a great experience in my life group last year.
I want to do that for somebody else this year.
I want to mentor somebody and take them under my wing.
I want to disciple the next generation.
Maybe it's actually inviting somebody to come and join you
next Sunday or at your first life group meeting
that you'll go to.
Maybe it's praying for someone in the classroom
or in the workplace
because you know they're struggling with some things.
Prayerfully consider that.
I can't give you all the ideas
that God might actually speak to you about,
but pray about that and say,
God, how do you want me to take my next steps?
And then third, don't settle for a temporary purpose.
We'll talk about this quite a bit this year.
Don't settle for a temporary purpose.
I would encourage all of us to realize today
we are where we are for a reason bigger
than we usually remember on a day-to-day basis.
For some of us, that's raising our kids.
For some of us, that's going to school,
middle school, high school.
For some of us, that's going to our workplace day by day
or whatever else it is that you're called to.
For some of you here, especially,
and many of you today, you're here for the first time
going to the University of Michigan
as a college or a grad student.
You're here at one of the best universities in the world.
Time Magazine says number five in the world.
Can you believe that?
I think it's number one.
you're here can you know that you're here for a purpose bigger than yourself
not just to collect a degree a piece of paper get the right go the right major figure out your
next steps god has a purpose for you here and your education is part of it but as he has a purpose
for you here to be part of his mission and his calling in the world in the church that's a joyful
thing to be part of as we